redpepper.ug 2008-09-12

# Red Pepper Uganda Online. Our Commitment To Your Privacy

Thank you for visiting the Red Pepper Online and reviewing our privacy policy. Our online policy is clear: We will collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us. This Web site is owned by the Red pepper Online and is fully committed to respecting your privacy and protecting your personal information. When you visit our Web site, we will not collect personal information unless you choose to use services that ask for personal information. 

Your personal information will not be used or disclosed for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with your consent or as required by law. Personal information will be retained only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes or as required by law. The government will not send you unsolicited electronic messages, and we will not permit third parties, such as service providers under government contract, to do so, unless you choose. Below is how we handle information about your visit to our website:

**Red Pepper Online Internet Security Policy**

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, our secure servers employ software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on our service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the available Computer Fraud and Abuse Acts and the International Information Infrastructure Protection Acts. 

Our privacy policy describes Red Pepper Online's current policies and practices with regard to personal data collected by Red Pepper Online. This privacy policy is independent from Red Pepper Publication’s offline personal data collection practices. The term "personal data" refers to personally identifiable information about you, such as your name, birth date, e-mail address or mailing address, and any other information that is identified with you personally, including your individual health information.

**Notification of Changes to This Policy**

Red Pepper Online is continually improving and adding new functionality and features to its website while and improving and adding to our existing products, services, and programs. Because of these ongoing changes, changes in the law, and the changing nature of technology, Red Pepper Online's data practices will change from time to time. If and when our data practices change, Red Pepper Online will reveal the changes on our website to notify you of the changes. We encourage you to check this page frequently. 

**Notification to Advertisers on Our Advertising Policy**

Red Pepper Online is intermittently adding new features and functionalities to the website. As it were, while improving the existing products, services, and programs, we have two categories of advertising sections. 

Content Driven Sections: With the exception of the Pictorial section, these will include the general pages that involve mostly content-based features. These sections are: Subscribe, About Us, Advertising, Privacy Policy, Contact Us, News Headlines, Gossip, Political Hysteria, Business, Spot Light, 3 Am, Columnists, Hyena's Whopper, Pepper Sport, Archives and Link To Us.

Context (Application) Driven Sections: These sections involve strictly sponsored pages because of the applications involved in running and managing them. For now, these sections are: Love Connection and Chat Room. The Pictorial section is also included here because of the nature of the content gathering process that goes into acquiring the best images from the best possible photographers.

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically**

In addition to the information you provide when you use our website, uses technology to collect anonymous information about the use of website. For example, we use technology to track how many visitors access our website, the date and time of their visit, the length of their stay, and which pages they view. We also use technology to determine which web browsers our visitors use and the address from which they accessed Red Pepper Online (for example, if they connected to a Red Pepper Online website by clicking on one of our banner ads). This technology does not identify you personally. 

It simply enables us to compile statistics about our visitors and their use of our sites. Red Pepper Online and our affiliates use this anonymous data and share it with third parties to improve the content and functionality of our websites, to better understand our customers and markets, and to improve our products and services. If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the website, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit, such as:

  1. The Internet domain (for example, "abcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account or “mak.ac.ug if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our website;

  2. The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;

  3. The date and time you access our site;

  4. The pages you visit; and

  5. If you linked to the Red Pepper Online website from another website, the address of that website.

We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors -- to learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record information about individuals and their visits. 

**Personal Data Collected Through Red Pepper Online**

Other than cookies, as described below, the only personal data Red Pepper Online currently collects through its websites is the information you voluntarily give us when you use the site. For example, you may use this site to contact Red Pepper Online with questions and comments. When you fill out a form on the website, you may provide your name and other contact information, including your company's name, your e-mail address, and your mailing address or the mailing address of your company or other personal information. 

If you do not wish to fill out all of the information on the form you are not required to do so. When you submit information to us through Red Pepper Online, you will receive a confirmation if you enter valid information. We offer the search features as a service to you. Red Pepper Online does not collect or retain any identifying information about you when you use the search features.

**Use of Personal Data Collected Through Red Pepper Online**

Red Pepper Online uses the personal data information you provide to answer your question or resolve your query. We use this information to help us improve the content and functionality of our website, to better understand our customers and markets, and to improve our products and services. Red Pepper Online uses this information to contact you in the future to tell you about products or services we believe will be of interest to you. 

If we do so, each communication we send you will contain instructions permitting you to "opt-out" of receiving future communications. Similarly, we may provide "subscription" e-mail services, either directly or through affiliates, which enable you to receive current news about Red Pepper Online products or related medical conditions and procedures. For all such services, we will provide an opportunity to "opt-out" of, or cancel, the subscription. 

**Cookies**

This site does NOT use the cookies that some Web sites use to gather and store information about your visits to their sites. A cookie is a small piece of information that is sent to your browser and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies do not damage your computer and they cannot be used to discover the identity of a user. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. This enables you to decide if you want to accept it or not and whether you are required to accept the cookie to view certain content. 

Red Pepper Online may use cookies to "persist" a user session — that is, to maintain connection with a user as he or she moves through an application or series of web pages. The purpose of cookies in this context is to remember user inputs. Personalization features also use cookies to identify groups of users and deliver appropriate content and services.

**Disclosure of Personal Data**

Red Pepper Online will not share some or all of the personal data collected with our associates or affiliates, UNLESS the data is used in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Red Pepper Online may share personal data collected through the website with third-party vendors who act for or on behalf of Red Pepper Online (for example, companies that provide support services to us, including data processing services, or that help us market our products and services). 

These companies may need information about you in order to perform their functions. These companies are not authorized to use the information we share with them for any other purpose. In addition, there may be some other, limited circumstances in which Red Pepper Online may share or transfer the personal data in our databases, for example, to comply with a legal requirement, for the administration of justice, to protect your vital interests, or in the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution, or similar event. 

While no method of data transmission is guaranteed against unlawful third party interception or other misuse, Red Pepper Online uses commercially reasonable efforts to ensure protection of your data including industry-standard encryption and offline security methods in our physical facilities (e.g., your data is protected onsite by our Information Assets Protection Policy).

**Children**

Red Pepper Online does not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of EIGHTEEN. If you are under eighteen, please do not give us any personal data. If you have reason to believe that a child has provided personal data to Red Pepper Online, please contact us immediately, and we will try to delete that information from our databases.

**Link to Other Sites**

Our privacy policy applies only to Red Pepper Online. We operate our website for numerous purposes and in different countries where different laws may apply. Our website has links to the websites of many other individuals and organizations. In a few cases, we link to private organizations, with their permission. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. 

Red Pepper Online contains hyperlinks to websites that are not operated by Red Pepper Online. These hyperlinks are provided for your reference and convenience only and do not imply any endorsement of the activities of these third-party websites or any association with their operators. Red Pepper Online does not control these websites and is not responsible for their data practices. We urge you to review the privacy policy posted on any site you visit before using the site or providing any personal data about yourself. 

**Governing Law**

This privacy policy forms part of our website Terms and Conditions and as such shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of Uganda.

**Questions about Red Pepper Online Policy**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or concerns about the way Red Pepper Online processes your personal data, please do not hesitate contact us.
